George Lardner Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Part I: Subject File, 1923-1997 (Box 1-285)
  - Kennedy, John F.
    - Assassination See also Containers 231-239, U. S. House of Representatives, Select Committee on Assassinations
      - General
        - Research material
          - Freedom of Information Act requests
            - Secret Service, 1955-1963, undated, (2 folders) (Box 143)
          - State Department, 1959-1967, 1977, undated, (4 folders)
          - Miscellany, 1964-1974
          - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1967, 1975-1991, undated, (2 folders)
      - Hosty, James P., 1975-1980 (Box 144)
      - Lifton, David, Best Evidence
        - Correspondence and notes, 1980-1981, n.d
        - Research material, 1975, 1980-1983, n.d
      - Mexico, 1963-1969, 1975-1977, undated
      - Monroe, Marilyn, 1985
      - Nosenko, Yuri, 1964, (2 folders)
      - Sturgis, Frank, and Marita Lorenz, 1975-1977, undated
      - U. S. Senate Select Committee to Study Government Operations with Respect to Intelligence Activities (Church Committee), 1975-1977, undated
      - Weisberg v. United States Dept. of Justice, 1964, 1975-1980, undated
    - White House years
      - Death and funeral
        - Articles, 1963-1964
        - Notes, 1963
      - Miscellaneous notes, undated
  - Kennedy, Robert F., assassination (Box 145)
    - Articles, 1970-1974
    - Book review, undated
    - Correspondence, 1968-1977, undated, (3 folders)
    - Interviews, 1969-1975, undated, (2 folders)
    - Notes
      - Miscellaneous, 1974-1975, undated
      - Notebooks, undated
    - Research material
      - Legal documents, 1970-1975, undated, (3 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, 1962-1983, undated, (5 folders) (Box 146)
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1968-1978, undated, (3 folders)
  - King, Martin Luther, Jr., assassination See also Containers 239-244, U. S. House of Representatives, Select Committee on Assassinations
    - Articles and correspondence, 1968-1979
    - Interviews and notes, 1978-1979
    - Research material (Box 147)
      - Freedom of Information Act Requests
        - Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1962-1983, (5 folders)
        - Weisberg v. Central Intelligence Agency
          - Legal documents, 1978-1979
          - Released documents
            - 1964-1967
            - 1968-1977, undated, (3 folders) (Box 148)
        - Weisberg v. United States Department of Justice, 1981-1985, undated
      - Miscellaneous, 1964, 1978, 1990-1994, undated
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1968, 1978-1983, undated
  - Kirkpatrick, Evron M. and Jeane J., 1981-1983, undated (Box 149)
  - Korean Airlines attack, undated
  - Ku Klux Klan See also Container 47, Civil rights
    - Articles and correspondence, 1964, undated
    - Notes, undated, (2 folders)
    - Research material
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1964, undated
  - Laborers' International Union of North America
    - Freedom of Information Act requests
      - 1982
        - Feb.
        - Mar. (Box 150)
        - Undated
    - Legal documents, 1982
    - Notes, undated
  - Lane, Mark, 1978-1980, undated
  - LaRouche, Lyndon H., 1981
  - Libya, sanctions, 1981-1986
  - Lie detectors
    - Correspondence and interviews, 1982-1983
    - Notes, 1983, undated
    - Presidential directive on safeguarding national security information
      - Articles and interviews, 1983
      - Notes, undated (Box 151)
      - Research material
        - General, 1983-1984
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1983
    - Research material
      - Hearings, U.S. House of Representatives
        - Committee on Government Operations, 1983
        - Committee on the Judiciary, 1982
      - Legal documents, 1923, 1966, 1978-1983
      - Miscellaneous, 1978-1984, undated
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1977-1984, undated, (3 folders) (Box 152)
      - Policies and procedures
        - Defense Department, 1975, 1982
        - Federal Bureau of Investigation, undated
        - Intelligence agencies, 1979
      - Studies
        - Defense Department, 1983
        - Law Enforcement Assistance Association, 1978
        - New York Civil Liberties Union, 1981
        - Office of Technology Assessment, 1983, (2 folders)
        - Tarlow, Barry, 1975 (Box 153)
        - U.S. House of Representatives, Committee on Government Operations, 1965, 1976
      - Tillson, John, 1982
      - Williams, Roy, 1980
  - Lobbying and special interest politics, 1977
  - Lockheed Shipbuilding Co., 1972, undated
  - Lugar, Richard
    - Articles, 1982
    - Interviews, 1982
    - Notes
      - Miscellaneous, 1982
      - Notebooks, 1982
    - Research material, 1970-1982, undated, (3 folders)
  - Lumber industry, 1972-1977
  - Mafia (Box 154)
    - Kansas City, Mo., skimming trial
      - Articles, 1983-1986, undated
      - Notes
        - Miscellaneous, 1983-1986, undated
        - Notebooks, 1985-1986, (5 folders)
      - Research material
        - Legal documents
          - 1979-1985, (2 folders)
          - 1986, undated, (2 folders) (Box 155)
        - Miscellaneous, 1983-1986, undated
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1971-1986, undated, (2 folders)
    - Miscellany
      - Notes, 1992, undated
      - Research material
        - Bender, Stanley, 1957-1981
        - Justice Department, 1978-1991
        - Legal documents, 1983-1985, undated (Box 156)
        - Miscellaneous, 1968, 1980-1981, undated
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1969-1971, 1981-1992, undated, (6 folders)
        - U.S. Senate Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations, 1982, 1988, undated, (4 folders) (Box 157)
  - Mandela, Nelson, 1990
  - Marcos, Ferdinand
    - Articles and correspondence, 1986
    - Notes
      - Miscellaneous, 1986, undated
      - Notebooks, 1986
    - Research material
      - Leases, 1965, 1971-1986
      - Legal documents
        - Azurin v. Raab, 1986, (2 folders)
        - Republic of the Phillippines v. Marcos, 1986, (2 folders) (Box 158)
        - Trajano v. Marcos, 1986
      - Miscellaneous, 1986
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1985-1986, undated, (3 folders)
  - McVeigh, Timothy James See Containers 188-190, Oklahoma City, Okla., bombing
  - Meat industry
    - Notes, undated
    - Research material, 1978-1979, (2 folders)
  - Meese, Edwin (Box 159)
    - Financial disclosure
      - Articles, 1987-1988, undated
      - Research material
        - "Baby Bell" telephone companies, stock certificates
          - General, 1988
          - Metzenbaum, Howard M., investigation, 1987
        - Correspondence, 1985-1987
        - Levin, Carl, investigation, 1987-1988
        - Lewin, Nathan (Meese's attorney), personal investments, 1987
        - Meese, Ursala
          - Bender family
            - Leases of property to the federal government, 1987-1988
            - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1988
          - National Multiple Sclerosis Society
            - Ambassadors' balls regarding fund-raising, 1980-1986, undated
            - General, 1988
          - UNESCO, Reform Observation Panel on, 1985
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1984-1988, undated
    - General
      - Articles and correspondence, 1988, undated
      - Notes, 1988
      - Research material
        - Confirmation and swearing in ceremony, 1985
        - Freedom of Information Act requests, Justice Department
          - Schedules, 1986-1987
          - Travel vouchers, 1985-1988, (4 folders) (Box 160)
          - Trips
            - 1981-1986, (5 folders)
            - 1987-1988, (7 folders) (Box 161)
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1981-1988, undated (Box 162)
    - McKay, James C., investigation
      - Articles and correspondence, 1987-1988
      - Interviews, 1988
      - Notes, 1987-1988
      - Research material
        - Correspondence, 1987-1988
        - Justice Department report, 1988
        - Legal documents, 1988
        - Levin, Carl, investigation, 1987-1988
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1987-1988
        - Press conference transcripts, 1988
        - Press releases, 1987-1988 (Box 163)
        - "Response of Edwin Meese III to the Report of Independent Counsel," 1988, (2 folders)
        - U.S. Senate Committee on the Judiciary, 1988
    - Resignation, 1988
      - Article and correspondence
      - Research material
        - Newspaper clippings and related material
        - Statement by Meese
  - Merola, Mario, death of, 1985-1988
  - Metcalf, Lee, and utility companies, 1964-1975
  - Miami, Fla., riots (Box 164)
    - Articles and correspondence, 1980
    - Interviews, 1980
    - Notes
      - Miscellaneous, 1980
      - Notebooks, 1980
    - Research material, 1978-1980, undated
  - Militias
    - Articles, 1995
    - Notes, 1995
    - Research material
      - Arizona, 1995
      - Arkansas, The Covenant, the Sword, and the Arm of the Lord (CSA), 1985-1988, 1995, undated, (2 folders)
      - Founding fathers and arms, 1967, 1992-1995, undated, (2 folders)
      - Idaho, 1995
      - Michigan, 1995
      - Montana, 1994-1995
      - Moody, Walter Leroy, Jr., 1993
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1939, 1966-1968, 1983-1995, undated, (5 folders) (Box 165)
      - U.S. Senate Judiciary Committee hearing, 1995
      - Virginia, 1995
      - Waco, Texas, 1993-1995, (2 folders)
  - Minimum wage
    - Articles, 1981
    - Interviews and notes, 1981, undated
    - Research material, 1979-1981, undated
  - Miscellaneous topics
    - Articles, correspondence, and notes, 1976-1985, undated
    - Research material, 1971, undated
  - Mobutu Sese Seko (Box 166)
    - Articles and notes, 1981, undated
    - Research material, 1981
  - Mondale, Walter, 1976-1979, undated
  - Monroe, Marilyn, 1985
  - Morison, Samuel Loring
    - Articles and correspondence, 1985-1986
    - Notes, 1985-1986
    - Research material
      - Legal documents
        - 1984-1987, (3 folders)
        - 1988, undated, (2 folders) (Box 167)
      - Miscellaneous, 1984-1986, undated
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1984-1986, undated
  - Multinational business corruption, 1975-1978, undated
  - National Archives and Records Administration
    - Presidential records
      - Articles, 1981-1993, undated
      - Correspondence, 1993
      - Interviews, 1980-1981, undated
      - Notes, 1975-1981, 1993, undated
      - Research material (Box 168)
        - Hearings, U.S. House Committee on Government Operations, 1978
        - Laws and statutes, 1976-1978, 1984, 1993, undated
        - Legal documents
          - Armstrong v. Executive Office of the President, 1991-1993, (3 folders)
          - Public Citizen v. Burke, 1988 (Box 169)
        - Miscellaneous, 1979-1981, 1992-1993, undated
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1974-1993, undated
        - Oberg, Lawrence, 1992-1993
        - Schnapper, M. B., 1977-1981, undated
    - Proposed Nixon library, Duke University, Durham, N.C.
      - Articles and notes, 1981, undated
      - Research material
        - Miscellaneous, 1981, undated
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1973-1981
  - National Commission on the Causes and Prevention of Violence, 1969
  - National Endowment for Democracy
    - Articles and notes, 1983, undated
    - Research material
      - Miscellaneous, 1983-1985, undated
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1983-1985, undated
  - National Security Agency See also Containers 107-120, Iran-Contra Affair, and Containers 177-187, North, Oliver (Box 170)
    - Articles, 1973-1978, 1984-1990
    - Correspondence, 1989
    - North, Oliver
      - Articles and notes, 1989, undated
      - Research material
        - Legal documents, 1986-1989, undated
        - Miscellaneous, 1980, 1987-1990
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1975, 1988-1989, undated
        - Reports, 1989
    - Notes, 1989-1990, undated
    - Pelton, Ronald W.
      - Articles and correspondence, 1986-1989
      - Research material
        - Legal documents, 1986, (2 folders)
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1986
    - Research material (Box 171)
      - Ball, Desmond, 1986-1989, undated
      - Budget proposal, 1990
      - Carter, William A. ("Billy"), 1980, undated
      - England, 1980, undated
      - Financial disclosures, 1989
      - Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act, 1978
      - Freedom of Information Act requests, 1989
      - Harris, William R., 1989
      - Information Security Oversight Office, symposium, 1988
      - Miscellaneous, 1984-1988, undated
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1975-1990, undated, (2 folders)
      - Prosecutive summary, 1977 (Box 172)
      - "Report, U.S. House Committee on Government Operations," undated
      - "Report on Inquiry into CIA-related Electronic Surveillance Activities," 1976
      - Rosenberg, Ethel and Julius, 1977-1986
      - U-2 airplanes, 1960, 1971
    - U.S. House Committee on Government Operations, hearings
      - Articles, 1975
      - Notes, 1975
      - Research material, 1975, undated
    - Wobensmith, John C.
      - Articles, undated
      - Correspondence, 1988-1990
      - Research material
        - Legal documents
          - Miscellaneous, 1987-1988, undated
          - Transcript of hearing, 1988, (4 folders) (Box 173)
        - Miscellaneous, 1975, 1985-1990, undated
  - Native Americans, Alaska earthquake, 1964
  - New Orleans, La., sniper
    - Articles and correspondence, 1973, undated
    - Research material, 1973
  - Newsmen's Privilege Act of 1973, 1971-1973, undated, (2 folders)
  - Nicaragua and the freedom fighters, 1979-1984, undated, (2 folders)
  - Nichols, James Douglas See Containers 188-190, Oklahoma City, Okla., bombing
  - Nichols, Terry Lynn See Containers 188-190, Oklahoma City, Okla., bombing
  - Nofziger, Franklyn C. ("Lyn") (Box 174)
    - Comet Rice Mills
      - Articles, 1986
      - Research material
        - Freedom of Information Act, State Department, 1981-1983
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1979-1986
    - Ethics in Government Act of 1978
      - Research material
        - Correspondence, 1986
        - Legal documents, 1987
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, circa 1982-1988
      - United States v. Nofzinger, 1987
    - General
      - Notes, 1986
      - Research material, 1982-1988
    - Independent Counsel Reauthorization Act of 1987
      - Articles, 1987-1988
      - Notes, 1987-1988
      - Research material
        - Correspondence, 1987
        - Financial reports, 1987-1988, (2 folders)
        - Legislation, 1987
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1986-1988
        - Press releases, 1987-1988
      - Morrison v. Olson, 1988
    - International Medical Centers (IMC), 1988
    - Long Island Lighting Co. (LILCO) (Box 175)
      - Notes, 1986
      - Research material, 1986-1988
    - North Slope Borough, Barrow, Alaska, transfer of federal gas field, 1982-1987
    - Wedtech
      - Economic Development Agency (EDA), 1983-1987
      - Fairchild Industries
        - Articles, 1987
        - Research material, 1979-1987, undated
      - Garcia Ordnance Corp.
        - Notes, 1988
        - Research material
          - Correspondence, Army Department, 1982-1987
          - General, 1981-1986
          - Legal documents, 1986
          - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1984-1988
      - General
        - Articles, 1986-1988
        - Notes, 1986
        - Research material
          - Freedom of Information Act requests, 1987
          - Legal documents, 1987
          - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1982-1989, undated
      - Pontoon contracts
        - Articles, 1987
        - Research material
          - Correspondence
            - Army Department, 1989
            - General, 1981, 1987
            - Navy Department, 1983-1988
            - Wallach, E. Robert, 1982-1984
          - Legal documents, 1987, undated
          - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1987, undated
      - Small Business Administration (SBA)
        - Articles, 1986
        - Research material
          - Correspondence, 1981-1988, undated
          - Freedom of Information Act requests, 1986-1987
          - General, 1982-1988, undated
          - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1982-1987, undated (Box 176)
      - United States v. Nofziger
        - Legal documents, 1989-1991
        - Notes, 1987, (5 folders)
  - Nixon, Richard M., taxes (Box 177)
    - Articles and notes, undated
    - Research material, 1969-1974, undated
  - North, Oliver See also Containers 107-120, Iran-Contra Affair; Containers 170-173, National Security Agency; and Container 227, Toobin, Jeffrey
    - Articles, 1987-1991, undated
    - Associated Press v. United States, 1989
    - Correspondence, 1989-1991
    - Interviews, 1988-1991
    - North v. Walsh, 1987-1989, (6 folders)
    - Research material (Box 178)
      - Case law, 1976-1977, undated
      - Excerpts, Oliver North, 1987-1989, undated
      - Hostages, 1985-1991, undated, (2 folders)
      - Independent counsel, 1979-1987, undated, (3 folders)
      - "Index to the Iran-Contra Hearings Summary Report," 1988
      - "Index to the Tower Commission Report," 1987
      - Jurors, 1987, undated
      - Miscellaneous, 1959, 1977, 1984-1995, undated
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1984-1991, (2 folders) (Box 179)
      - Testimony
        - Casey, William J., 1986-1987, undated
        - McFarlane, Robert C., 1989
    - In re Associated Press (89-0099), 1989
    - In re Sealed Case (87-0139), 1987
    - In re Sealed Case (87-5168), 1987, (2 folders)
    - Tribe, Laurence H., 1988
    - United States v. North (Box 180)
      - Legal documents
        - Exhibits
          - Defendants, 1984-1986, (4 folders)
          - Government, 1984-1986, (4 folders)
          - Government, 1984-1986, (3 folders) (Box 181)
          - Hearings, 1987-1988
        - General
          - 1988
            - Mar.-Nov., (4 folders)
            - Dec. (Box 182)
          - 1989
            - Jan.-Feb., (6 folders)
            - Mar.-July, (9 folders) (Box 183)
          - 1991 (Box 184)
          - Undated
        - Grand jury, instructions, 1987
        - Jurors, instructions and notes, 1989
      - Notes
        - Miscellaneous, 1989
        - Notebooks
          - 1989
            - Feb., (5 folders)
            - Mar. (Box 185)
              - 1-23, (7 folders)
              - 28-31, (2 folders) (Box 186)
            - Apr.
              - 3-13, (5 folders)
              - 14-29, (3 folders) (Box 187)
            - May-June, (2 folders)
    - United States v. North, 1989-1991, (2 folders)
    - United States v. Reed, 1989-1990
  - Oklahoma City, Okla., bombing (Box 188)
    - Arkansas gun robbery
      - Legal documents, 1994-1995, undated, (3 folders)
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1995
    - Articles and correspondence, 1995, undated
    - Notes, 1995, (2 folders)
    - Research material
      - Legal documents
        - In re Nichols, 1995
        - United States v. Fortier, 1995
        - United States v. McVeigh (96-CR-68-M), 1996
        - United States v. McVeigh (CR 95-110-A), 1995
        - United States v. McVeigh (M-95-98-H), 1995, (2 folders)
        - United States v. Nichols (95-80361), 1995 (Box 189)
        - United States v. Nichols (M-95-105-H), 1995
      - McVeigh, Timothy James, military record, 1990-1995, undated
      - Miscellaneous, 1995, undated
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1993-1996, undated, (8 folders) (Box 190)
  - Paisley, Mel, 1988, undated (Box 191)
  - Peace movement, 1982-1983, undated
  - People to People International, China exchange, 1988
  - Polk, George, murder
    - Notes, 1985-1986, undated
    - Research material
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1948-1956, 1977, 1983-1985, undated
      - Released documents, 1948-1949, (3 folders)
  - Presidential election campaigns For additional material see Containers 5-9, Campaign spending (Box 192)
    - 1972 primaries
      - Florida
        - Articles, 1972
        - Interviews and notes, 1972
        - Research material
          - Campaign literature and miscellany, 1972
          - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1972, (2 folders)
      - General
        - Articles, 1972
        - Expenses, 1971-1972
        - Interviews, 1971-1972
        - Notes, 1971-1972, (2 folders)
        - Notes, 1972, (3 folders) (Box 193)
        - Notes, 1972 (Box 194)
        - Research material
          - Campaign literature and miscellany, 1971-1972
          - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1971-1972
          - Press pool reports, 1972
      - Indiana
        - Articles and notes, 1972
        - Research material
          - Campaign literature and miscellany, 1972, undated
          - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1972
      - Wisconsin
        - Articles, notes, and miscellany, 1972
        - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1972
    - 1976
      - General election, Peter Camejo, 1976
      - Primaries (Box 195)
        - Carter, Jimmy, candidacy, 1970-1976, (2 folders)
        - Florida
          - Notes, 1976
          - Research material, 1975-1976
        - North Carolina, 1976
  - President's Commission on Organized Crime
    - Articles, 1986
    - Notes, 1986, undated
    - Research material
      - Miscellaneous, 1986, undated
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1983-1986 (Box 196)
      - Report, undated, (3 folders)
  - Public gaming (Box 197)
    - Articles, 1976
    - Interviews, undated
    - Notes, 1976, undated
    - Research material
      - Commission on the Review of the National Policy Toward Gambling
        - Membership and meeting records, 1976, undated
        - Reports, 1974-1976, (4 folders)
        - Reports, 1974-1976 (Box 198)
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1974-1976
      - Public Gaming Research Institute, annual conference, 1976
  - Puerto Rico, 1976-1979, undated
  - Quayle, Dan
    - Articles and correspondence, 1988, undated
    - Interviews and notes
      - Miscellaneous, 1988, undated
      - With index, 1988, undated
    - Research material
      - Bell, Tom, and Center for Naval Analyses controversy, 1980-1983, undated
      - Congressional voting record, 1976-1988, undated
      - Financial disclosure, 1980-1988, undated
      - Indiana National Guardsman, 1969, 1975 (Box 199)
      - Miscellany, 1967, undated
      - Muncie Newspapers, Inc., 1977-1978
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1970-1988, undated, (7 folders)
      - Senate campaign, 1977-1980
      - United States v. Continental Training Services, 1987-1988
  - Reagan, Ronald, transition team (Box 200)
    - Articles, 1980
    - Interviews, notes, and research material
      - Brady, James, 1980, undated
      - Defense Department, 1979-1980, undated
      - Energy Department, 1977-1980, undated
      - Environmental Protection Agency, 1980, undated
      - Federal Communications Commission, 1980, undated
      - Health and Human Services, Department of, 1979-1980, undated
      - Interior Department, 1980, undated
      - Labor Department, 1980, undated
      - Miscellaneous, 1980, undated
      - Nuclear Regulatory Commission, 1980, undated
      - State Department and Marion Smoak, 1980, undated
  - Rehnquist, William H.
    - Articles, 1986
    - Correspondence, 1986
    - Interviews and notes, 1986, undated
    - Interviews and notes, 1986, undated, (4 folders) (Box 201)
    - Research material
      - Camp Hindenburg, Grafton, Wis., 1937-1938, 1986, undated
      - Chief Justice nomination
        - Congressional floor debates, 1986, (2 folders)